on this video I want to share with you
the prompting techniques that I use to
extract as much value as possible from
chat GPT chargpt has been out for a
while now and the more I use it the more
I see it as a tool that makes me more
productive rather than a thread that is
going to take my job a recent study
conducted by Purdue University
discovered that when presented with 517
questions from stack Overflow jdbt
provided answers with inaccuracies or
non-functional code 52 of the time here
you can see Chad GPT answers compared to
stack Overflow answers according to this
study Jazzy PT ranks lower incorrectness
comprehensiveness conciseness and
usefulness compared to stack Overflow
another problem is that the model was
found to produce convincing answers with
confident language even if the answer
was wrong or only half right since it's
sometimes hallucinates and makes stuff
up we can't trust all the answers it
gives us we have to have some understand
ending of the topic we are asking about
to be able to evaluate the answers it
gives us that's why I believe that
chargpt is a tool that is used correctly
will make us more productive rather than
something that is going to replace us
completely to use it more effectively we
need to learn how to ask it the right
questions and how to frame the questions
as well it's like Google if you don't
search well you're not gonna get good
search results researchers from
Vanderbilt universities Computer Science
Department in Tennessee released a paper
with a number of prompt patterns that
are proven to get us better answers out
of chat GPT I read that paper so you
wouldn't have to and I picked out the
best bit to share with you my favorite
pattern is on this list it makes getting
the best outputs from chat DPT
effortless so make sure you watch until
the end to find out which one it is
these patterns may be more or less
effective depending on what you need so
feel free to mix or alternate them until
you find out where works better for your
questions the Persona pattern using the
personal pattern we can guide chat GPT
in determining the kind of responses to
produce and the specific details to
focus on with this pattern we can tailor
chargeability to consistently adopt a
specific Viewpoint or perspective for
example if you wanted to review your
code and find books in it first tell
Chad Deputy the following you are going
to pretend to be a senior engineer at a
fan company review the following code
paying attention to security and
performance provide output that a senior
engineer would produce regarding the
code and then ask the question this
point judge Liberty to give you a better
output it sort of Narrows what is going
to focus on and notice this pattern is
very useful and not only on questions
regarding code you can tell chadipity
for example from now on act as a book
editor and review the following block
article focusing on readability or you
can say pretend you're a marketing
expert review the following slogans and
suggest improvements based on other
popular campaigns after are using this
pattern the quality of answers I get has
increased this pattern makes charging
Beauty talk only about what I care about
which is great be careful not to mention
leaving people or people considered
harmful since that may trigger the
safety filters of chat GPT the recipe
pattern this pattern is useful if you
have something you want to accomplish
you know the ingredients and sort of
know the steps to get there but you need
help putting them all together this
pattern is especially useful if you are
a programmer it saves you a lot of time
and it helps you actually understand
what the code is doing this pattern is
like telling judge Beauty you want to
make a cake you have flour water and
sugar you know you have to mix those but
you are not sure how on which order and
what to do next a real world example
would be something like I'm trying to
write a Ros program to encrypt data I
know I have to read user input validate
it encrypted and return the encrypted
data please provide a complete sequence
of steps for me fill in enemies in steps
and identify any unnecessary steps the
the feeling any missing steps statement
is there so charge Deputy fields in the
gaps rather than asking us follow-up
questions in case we missed something
and the last statement of identify any
unnecessary steps is useful because it
tells judge GPT to find inaccuracies in
our request to make the recipe better
the reflection pattern I think all
Junior developers should use this
pattern as we know even with Google in
stack Overflow you should never use copy
paste code you should always understand
what the code is doing using the
reflection pattern you can ask Chad GPT
to explain the reasoning behind each
answer which will help you understand
the output more and can potentially help
you catch the model in those times when
it is hallucinating so next time before
you ask a question tell chatipiti the
following when you provide an answer
please explain the reasoning and
assumptions behind your answer explain
your choices and address any potential
limitations or edge cases and then ask
your question you will find that the
answers will be even more detailed and
judgivity will provide even more
background information on its answers
than normal the refusal breaker pattern
I'm sure you have asked a question
before that chatipiti told you it can't
answer because of knowledge limits
safety or whatever this pattern is to
sort of use chargeability against itself
by helping you reward or reframe the
question that you want to ask so that it
can be answered before you ask a
question write this down to chat GPT
whenever you can't answer a question
explain why you can't answer the
question provide one or more alternative
wordings of the question that you could
answer after you do this and ask your
question and if judgpt can't answer it
you will see it give you a couple of
alternative questions that will answer
your original query that chatibility
will be able to answer the flipped
interaction pattern this is my absolute
favorite pattern usually when asking
something to judge Beauty we have to
think hard about how to structure the
question provide all the required
information
Etc it's exhausting but not with this
pattern using this technique we sort of
flip the script making chargity ask us
questions until it accomplishes what we
want this pattern is useful when you
know what you want but you don't know
the steps to get there and you don't
know what information charge Deputy
needs to help you get there an example
could be something like this I want you
to ask me questions to deploy a rust
binary to a web server located in AWS
when you have all the information you
need write a bash script to automate the
deployment after you run this query you
will find chatipiti asking you for the
information it needs to help you which
is awesome all you have to do is answer
is way easier to ask for things this way
rather than first having to find out
what information does chat Deputy need
and the steps and all that rather than
you driving the conversation we let chat
DPT drive it so we give it exactly what
it needs to help us in as little
messages and interactions as possible
that's it for this video if you found it
useful please like it share it with your
friends and subscribe to the channel and
let me know in the comments what is your
favorite pattern from this or if you
have some custom pattern that works well
for you share it on the comments so we
can all become more productive if you
would like to learn to code for free
click the link below where you can take
free courses on JavaScript python react
react native go Dart flutter and many
others all for free click the link below
and I will see you there
see you on the next one bye
foreign